uh we're going to be talking about what
happens uh to a person when they die
uh what is the condition of death
according to the Bible and so uh let's
go ahead pray we're going to ask the
Lord to lead us in this study and um May
our eyes be open let's do that now
Heavenly Father
bless us Lord as we go on this uh
Journey Through the scriptures to see
what you have to say about the wages of
sin which is death help us Lord to
understand clearly this subject
um that we will not be fooled or
deceived by the enemy we pray this in
Jesus name amen and amen
um so I have entitled the sermon today
uh dead or alive
dead or alive
what happens to a person when
they die that's the question that we're
looking at what happens to a person when
they die uh give me one moment here I I
think my slides may be backward I'm just
going to change that out real quick here
so again the question is what happens to
a person when they die
um
the first thing I want you to understand
is is this
the enemy of souls has used this subject
to lead astray
countless people
how do we withstand
the
the devices of the enemy
how do we withstand the devices of the
anime I want you to notice what the
Bible says will happen at the end of
time
in Matthew 24 24 the Bible says for
there shall arise false Christ and false
prophets
and shall sow great signs and wonders in
so much that if it were possible they
shall deceive the very elect they shall
deceive the very elect so
how do we
avoid being deceived how do we avoid
um being led astray by by Satan how do
we avoid being led astray by false
christs and false prophets well our best
example is in Jesus himself
I want you to notice in Matthew chapter
4 Jesus has confronted the enemy
Satan has met him in the wilderness and
and Jesus
uh goes head to head with Satan three
times
and three times Jesus answers the
challenges of Satan in this way Matthew
4 verse 4 but he answered and said it is
written man shall not live by bread
alone but by every word that proceedeth
out of the mouth of god notice that it
is written
notice again in verse 7 Jesus said unto
him it is written again thou shall not
tempt the Lord thy God notice again with
me Matthew 4 verse
Psalm Matthew 4 whoa
Matthew 4 and verse 9.
Matthew 4 verse 9 verse 10. then save
Jesus unto him get the hints for it is
written that's the worst of the Lord thy
God and him only shout thou serve so
what we see here is that the way Jesus
withstood the enemy was with the word of
God
you cannot go wrong with the word of God
but I will tell you that in one of these
Temptations Satan actually quotes the
word of God
and miss and and Miss applies it
so not only do we need to be careful
about standing on the word of God but we
also need to be careful about
misapplying the word of God put a one in
the chat if that makes sense
we need to be careful because Satan can
take the very words of God and misapply
them and he has done so
in a very serious way when it comes to
this subject
so we're going to ask ourselves a couple
of questions and the first question
we're going to ask is is very simple the
question is what is a soul
what is a soul that's the first thing we
must understand
as we open the subject of what happens
to a person when they die so the
question is what is a soul we're going
to go back to the script to the text
to the Bible and we'll look at Genesis
chapter 2 and verse 7. the Bible says
here
and the Lord God
formed Man Out of the Dust of the ground
and breathed into his nostrils the
breath of life and Man became a living
Soul Man became a living soul I want you
to notice that the text does not say
that man received a living soul but it
says that man became a living Soul so in
looking at man looking at Adam
he himself was a living soul
he did not have a soul
he was a soul
put that one in the chat if you
understand thus far that according to
the very first description of man in the
Bible the Bible says that he was a soul
not that he had a soul but that he was a
soul so now let's look at this word soul
and I want you to note uh what the word
means is the Hebrew word nefesh and it
means properly a breathing creature so
Man became a breathing creature that's
what the text says
a soul therefore is a breathing
creature
put a two in the chat if I haven't lost
anyone thus far we're taking this very
slowly we're just going through the word
a living soul is a creature
now
uh let me point out one of the very
first deceptions that that that is out
there and that have that Millions have
bought into
so many people think that that
man has a soul
and and that he is because he has a soul
he's different from the animal world
right because the animal world they
don't have souls
but man has a soul and that's what sets
him apart but I want you to notice this
so remember what we said was the the
Hebrew word for soul is the word nephesh
so I want you to notice uh Genesis 1 and
verse 21 verse 20 24. Genesis 1 verse 24
the Bible says
and God said let the Earth bring forth
let me put that up on the screen and God
said let the Earth bring forth the
living creature
after his kind cattle and creeping
things and the beasts of the earth after
his kind and it was so that word
creature is the same word nephesh used
for Man became a living soul
we see it again in Genesis 1 21 and God
created great whales and every living
creature that moveth which the waters
brought forth abundantly after their
kind every winged filed after his kind
and God saw that it was good so uh what
we what we see here is that the living
creature is also described as a soul
now how is that even possible
how is a living man
and a living Beast how were they both
being described as Souls
well it's very simple a soul is a living
creature it doesn't matter what kind of
creature it is a soul is a living being
a being that has a body and has breath
so remember
when the Bible says that God created man
it says he created him out of the Dust
of the ground and he breathed into his
nostrils the breath of life and then Man
became a living Soul so let's break this
down even further
when God created Man Out of the Dust was
he a living being
yes or no was he a living being so when
when God forms the shape of Adam is Adam
alive at that moment is he a living
being is he a soul
yes or no no he is just dust
a body watch this all a body without
breath is not a what
I'm listening I'm hearing you by faith a
body without breath is not a soul
are y'all catching this a body without
breath is not a living creature
it's a body
it has no life in it so it cannot be a
soul it cannot be a living creature a
breathing creature okay
so the Bible says that so think of the
the body
think of this in terms of a computer the
body is the hardware
of the computer
the body is the hardware so think when
God created Man Out of the Dust that was
the hardware and now the Bible says that
he breathed into his nostrils the Breath
of Life
he breathed into the man's nostrils the
Breath of Life think of the breath of
Lies life as the electricity
if your computer doesn't have
electricity it's not going to power on
put a one in the chat if this makes
sense so so far
so watch this then
it is only after dust
and breath
or hardware and electricity come
together
that a living soul is formed
does that make sense are y'all following
a living soul is dust plus breath think
of it like this
when the computer hardware and the
electricity come together that's where
you have the software you turn the
computer on you got the software the
software is the intelligence
are you with me
you plug out the computer
guess what happens
you have no more salt the electricity
makes the intelligence inaccessible
so what we see here then is that it is
breath plus body that creates a living
Soul a being
what is that breath it's the breath of
god notice with me notice notice with me
Job chapter 27 verse 3 all the while my
breath is in me and the spirit of God is
in my nostrils wow pretty simple right
all the while my brothers and me and the
spirit of God is in my nostrils what did
God breathe into Adam what did God
breathe into Adam to bring him to life
he breathed into him the Breath of Life
what the Bible calls the spirits
the spirit is is the breath of life it's
not so look
every living being on the planet
watch this now every living being on the
planet is alive by the spirit of God now
watch this it doesn't mean that every
living being has the Holy Spirit
did y'all catch what I just said
every person who every living being on
the planet is alive by the Breath of God
the spirit of God but that does not mean
that every living being has the Holy
Spirit
okay
so let me just show you one more before
we move to our next question Isaiah 2
verse 22 CeCe from man whose breath is
in his nostrils for where is he to be
accounted of so again just verifying the
Bible is using these terms pretty much
the same way the Breath of God the
spirit of God is what gave man life we
are alive because of God
so a being a living being whether has a
body and breath that's what makes a soul
that's what makes a soul okay
I'm going to show you just a few more
examples here notice with me Genesis
chapter 12 Genesis 12 and verse 5.
in Genesis 12 5 the Bible says and Abram
took Sarah his wife and lot his brothers
sons and all their substance that they
had gathered and the souls that they had
gotten in Heron and they went forth to
go into the land of Canaan and into the
land of Canaan they came so let me ask
you a question did Abram walk out of
um heron
with
intangible Souls following him
yes or no
what is the text saying here
what is it calling Souls it's talking
about people and it uses the word souls
to describe people
so here's what we're doing guys we're
just going through the Old Testament
we're gonna go through the New Testament
as well but for now we're just going
through the Old Testament and we're
seeing okay when God created man the
entire man was a soul he didn't have a
soul he was a soul body plus breath
equals a complete being a living Soul
the same thing with animals they are
living creatures so thus far we see that
the word soul is used to describe actual
people notice again with me
notice again with me uh Genesis chapter
46 verse 22 these are the sons of Rachel
which were born to Jacob all the souls
were 14.
all the souls were all the people that's
what it's saying all the people there
were 14
offspring that Rachel had okay
so I'm not Rachel by the way but uh um
anyway y'all get the point we're talking
about souls people how about this one
how about Joshua chapter 11
Joshua chapter 11
or we can go Exodus chapter 1 and verse
5. and all the souls that came out of
the Lawns of Jacob were 70 Souls
70 Souls so so how are we doing so far
we're seeing that the Old Testament uses
the word souls to describe people
all right to describe people to describe
living creatures whether they're people
or animals they're a living being
meaning a soul
so what we see thus far is that man does
not have a soul because this is part of
the belief where when a person dies the
soul separates from the body
you're going to see something really
amazing here just keep following me okay
so let's go to our next question what is
death what is death that's the question
we have now according to the Bible
according to the Old Testament what is
death well let's go to the scripture and
we're going to find that God himself
defines what death is God himself
defines what death is let me just read
this text I I meant to put this up here
but notice what it says and they smote
all the souls that were there in with
the edge of the sword utterly destroying
them there was not any left to what's
that word y'all
to breathe
so I just want you to know taken from
Joshua 11 11 how it says these Souls
were killed with the edge of the sword
now remember this watch the show
in popular thought a soul is an
intangible thing so how do you kill a
soul with a sword
how do you kill a soul with the edge of
the sword how do you kill something that
you can't touch according to Hollywood
and according to many beliefs even
within Christianity that the soul is
some intangible thing how do you kill
according to Joshua 11 they smote all
the souls let me put it back up on the
screen they smote all the souls that
were therein with the edge of the sword
utterly destroying them
there was not any left to breathe
all right not any left to breathe so
again we see here that this is very
clear that a soul is a living being now
let's talk about this this thing of
death
God himself describes death in Genesis 2
verse 17 God tells Adam and Eve but of
the tree of the knowledge of Good and
Evil you shall not eat of it for in the
day you eat thereof you shall surely die
so this is the first time the word death
write the description of death is made
in the scriptures Adam and Eve are told
they're not into the street otherwise
you will surely die well we know that
they eat from the tree in Genesis 3 19
the Bible says in this when God comes to
Adam and Eve in the garden and this is
the this is what he tells them this is
the punishment in the sweater thy face
shall thou eat bread till thou return
unto the ground
for out of it that was taken for dust
you are and unto dust you shall return
let me read it again
in the sweat of thy face shalt thou eat
bread till thou return unto the ground
for out of it that was taken for dust
you are and unto dust you shall return
let's break this down you guys
according to this text
death
is a return
to the condition in which you were in
before you were created
put a one in the chat if that makes
sense everyone this is God himself
speaking
God says Adam
you were taken out of the Dust
you're going to return to the Dust
so death is as someone put in the chat
the reversal of the creation process
so here's a question that we must ask
them
what condition was man in before God
created him
that's a question
when when if we go back if we reverse
the process right when does man become a
living being
it is when God breathes into his
nostrils the Breath of Life
right so dust no life no consciousness
no consciousness in the dust put a one
in the chat if you all agree with that
was there any Consciousness in the dust
no consciousness in the dust was there
any Consciousness in the breath that God
breathed into the nostrils of Adam like
that God breathed was Adam already
existing
in breath somewhere else you know in God
or wherever and then God says all right
Adam this a man I'm about to put you
into this dust and Adam's like all right
I'm ready to go and like was Adam
existing before he was existing no not
in the dust not in the Breath of God the
Breath of God was simply the electricity
so when God breathes into his nostril
the Breath of Life Adam's Consciousness
is not in that breath
it's that's just the Breath of God
so it's not until dirt and the Breath of
God mingle that man becomes a living
being and Consciousness is now a
combination of dust plus breath equals
Consciousness I can think I can see I
can feel ah I'm alive
so what happens when the electricity is
removed what happens when the plug is
pulled what happens when death is the
process
of returning to the condition I
shouldn't say the process death is the
returning to the condition in which you
were in before you had life
what does that mean what does that tell
us
there's going to be very profound you
guys
death
equals
you're dead
now I know that sounds like you're wait
wait what
you will be shocked at how many people
do not realize this death means you're
dead
death means you have no life notice the
title of the sermon
dead or alive it's a question when Adam
was not created Was he alive
yes or no put a one in the chat
if you would agree that when Adam was
not created
he was not alive
all right when Adam came to life was he
dead
now I know I know it is
what but honestly I need you to
understand this
foreign
you cannot be dead and alive
put away that sounds that that's a
profound statement y'all trust me
you cannot be dead and alive at the same
time you are either dead or alive
you are either dead or alive you cannot
be dead and alive so God is clearly
telling us that death is the opposite of
being alive if you're alive you're not
dead if you're dead you're not alive now
y'all are probably laughing like Pastor
everybody knows that really wait until
we get a little bit further into the
study
so let's keep moving uh Psalm by the way
by the way
so if you're hearing this for the first
time I already I know where you might
you're already in the New Testament
you're right wait a minute pastor but
what about hold
I got you
just just stay with me stay with me we
just stand in the Old Testament first
okay so notice what the Bible says in
psalm
in Psalm 104 and verse 29. notice what
it says Thou hidest thy face talking
about God they are troubled you take
away their breath
they die and return to their dust so
what does the bible describe here death
as
when the breath is when God's breath is
taken away what do they do do they
continue living
no they die
and do what return to the dust return to
the condition in which they were in
before they were created here's my
question was man conscious before he was
created yes or no
thank you
was man did a man have a conscience
before he was created yes or no there
should be a whole bunch of notes in the
chat therefore
to return to the condition in which you
were in before you were alive meaning
death
that is your returning to a state in
which you have no conscience
you are not alive the plug has been
pulled the without the electricity there
can be no operating computer
does the bible verify this
notice with me Ecclesiastes chapter 9
verse 5 for the living know that they
shall die but the dead know not anything
neither have they any more a reward for
the memory of them is forgotten also
their love and their hatred and their
Envy is now perished neither have they
any more abortioned forever in anything
that is done under the sun now I want
you to pause here just for a second
can we agree right now that at least
according to the Old Testament because
some of you might be thinking about
right now well in the New Testament that
change we'll get to that but can we
agree that as of right now what we have
seen from the Old Testament and we're
not done yet is that
a dead person is actually dead
like he's actually dead he has no
conscience
he can't think feel he doesn't have love
joy he doesn't feel pain nothing he is
dead he ceases to exist
as a living being
the dust and the breath are separated
meaning the dust is now inoperable and
the breath which is simply the Breath of
God it goes back to God
some people think no no the breath is
the actual consciousness of the person
and that's what goes to God so that
means then that everybody's in heaven
Hitler
the worst killers in the world
everybody's in heaven because the Bible
God every person that dies God takes
their breath with them with them he
pulls his breath and it goes back to God
so that means everybody's in heaven man
let's celebrate
well maybe not right
the breath cannot be the actual thinking
part of a person
otherwise everybody's in heaven
so
um let's let's put up another one let's
put up another one uh Psalm 146 verse 4
his breath going forth he returns to his
Earth in that very day his thoughts
perish
yes yes yes the Bible is pretty
consistent here
we're seeing a very clear picture in
that very day his thoughts perish
so
as Ezekiel chapter 8 and verse 4 verse 4
verifies the Bible says behold All Souls
are mine all people are mine
as the soul of the father
saw also the soul of the son meaning as
the life of the father saw also the life
of the son is mine
and the soul that sinneth it shall die
now I need you to catch us y'all
because there's a lot of people out
there who believe that the soul cannot
die
but according to the Old Testament the
soul dies
God says the soul that sinneth it shall
die meaning the person that sins he
shall die and what is death I'll take my
breath your thoughts will perish meaning
that you have no knowledge of anything
anything
you are
in the ground
you are asleep notices Genesis 35 Verse
18 it came to pass as her soul was in
departing for she died so what does it
mean her soul was in departing what it
simply means is that her life was
leaving her
her life was leaving her so some people
think Oh look The Soul this conscious
entity is coming out of the body no
that's not what the text is saying it's
saying her life was departing she was
dying that's what it literally says for
she died that she called his name benoni
meaning she gives her son this name but
no one I and then Benjamin I mean and
then uh uh Jacob says no uh call him
Benjamin
um and so you got that whole story but
the point here is that see her life was
leaving her her life was leaving her so
I want you to notice this now notice how
the Bible cons in the Old Testament how
it consistently describes this watch
this
and Solomon slept
with his fathers and was buried in the
city of David his father
so what does that mean Solomon slept
with his fathers
what does that mean Solomon slept with
his fathers
what does sleep mean here
it means he died
so the Bible here is calling death a
sleep
Solomon slept not by himself but with
his fathers who were his fathers
everybody in his lineage before him so
the text is telling us here is that not
only is Solomon sleep asleep but all his
fathers are also asleep
one in the chat if y'all got that
and Hezekiah slept with his fathers and
they buried him in the chiefs of the of
the sepulchers of the sons of David and
all Jews inhabitators of Jerusalem did
honor him at his death
are you catching this
the Old Testament continually uses the
term slept with his father slept with
his father's meaning he died and was
buried just like his father before him
and his father before him and his father
before him and what are they doing there
sleeping meaning they have no knowledge
of anything that is done under the sun
that's what he read in Ezekiel chapter
uh in uh Ecclesiastes write chapter nine
to living know that they shall die but
the dead don't know anything now
why is this important to understand
because in the Old Testament God gives
us a law and by the way
this is the reason why many Christians
don't celebrate Halloween but
interestingly enough
they don't realize
that the reason that they don't
celebrate Halloween
they also Embrace that very reason
so for the for the typical Christian
it's like oh you know those are evil
spirits and we shouldn't have anything
to do with evil spirits
but hold on a second
I want you to notice what God Said
in The Book of Leviticus chapter 19
verse 31.
regard not then that have familiar
spirits neither seek after Wizards to be
defiled by them I am the Lord your God
so why does Jesus say regard not them
that have familiar spirits so it's very
simple
a familiar spirit
what would kind of be like
someone you know like hey you know you
know somebody from hey I know that guy
you know he's familiar
a familiar Spirit would be those who
profess to to be in communication with
familiar spirits will be someone who
says I can contact the dead so think
psychics think necromancers they claim
to be able to contact the dead but God
says don't contact the dead now I got a
question for you
I want you to think this through with me
okay
um
is mankind allowed to communicate with
God
yes or no one in the chat if the answer
is yes
are we called to communicate with God
God is in heaven are we called to
communicate with God yes God says I want
you to communicate with me all right
very good uh can mankind communicate
with angels
does God has a pro does God have a
Prohibition against man Talking to
Angels
no we see man and Angels talking in the
Bible
we see it happening right Gabriel comes
to Daniel so
No Angels have brought messages to man
and and man have talked with angels so
God is like okay mankind you can talk to
God you can talk to me you can talk to
angels but I want you to think this
through
if God says don't contact the dead don't
try to contact the dead and the dead are
in heaven
why would God allow us
to talk to him
to talk to angels but the people in
heaven nah they're off limits you can't
talk to them I want you to think that
through for a moment
well God you know just imagine heaven
and and you know man God is like who
shall I send let me let me send one of
the angels and the name's like cool who
else can I send to go speak to humanity
and and a human right you know a person
that has died and it's like hey I'm up
here in heaven I would love to go speak
to my loved one why would God be like no
not you no no no no no you all can't go
Only Angels
no that doesn't make any sense does it
the reason why God prohibits
communication with the dead is because
the dead are wait for it
dead
asleep
they have no knowledge
they're in the dust of the ground
so whoever that is you're talking to is
not your dead loved one
did y'all catch that
the reason why God says do not
communicate with familiar spirits is
because those familiar spirits are not
who you think they are
they are spirits of devils
call somewhere else in the Bible they
are spirits of devils
seeking to deceive
I'll show you an example
in the Old Testament
let's go to the text y'all might
remember the story of Samuel or Saul
whom the Bible says turned away from God
and then Saul is trying to talk to God
and God is not communicating with Saul
at all
and now I want you to notice I want you
to notice first of all let me read
Isaiah 8 19 and when they shall say unto
you seek unto them that have familiar
spirits and unto Wizards that Peep and
that mutter should not of people seek
unto their God for the living to the
dead in other words the text is saying
why would you try to communicate with
the Dead
when you can seek the living
we're told to seek the living not the
dead and there's a reason why because
the dead are dead you watch the cell you
cannot be dead and alive at the same
time
that does not make any sense you are
either dead or you are alive
right so watch what happens in first
Samuel chapter 28 verse 6 the Bible says
and when Saul inquired of the Lord the
Lord answered him not neither by dreams
nor by your room nor by Prophets
now remember God is not speaking to Saul
at all
Saul's probation has been cut off
so notice what Saul does in verse 7 then
set Saul unto his servants seek me a
woman that has a familiar spirit
that's already an Abomination to God
it's already demonic right there
he says that I may go to her and inquire
her and his servant said unto him behold
there's a woman that has a familiar
Spirit at Endor
reading on
yeah we're just going to skip let me
just explain the story to you
so in this story the Bible says that the
woman pulls up this the pulls up Samuel
now if you read the text
it says it was the form
of Samuel
wait it actually says that Saul
perceived or thought that it was Samuel
so this being is covered in a cloth and
he's speaking and he tells Saul that
he's gonna die the following day now I
want you to note something here
because if you look up
let me go back here let me go back
so when it says here in in verse 7
um that the woman had a familiar spirit
I want you to note something here
because
whoa
wow
all right let me go back here
my slides are kind of acting up so I'ma
just try to move on here part of the
definition of this of of having a
familiar spirit I want you to note here
just look at that word ventriloquist
ventriloquist that's what I want you to
focus on
ventriloquist
listen a ventriloquist is a person who
can speak or utter sounds so that they
seem to come from somewhere else
especially an Entertainer who makes
their voice appear to come from a dummy
of a person or an animal so let me ask
you a question
Saul doesn't see
Saul doesn't see it let me see all right
hopefully y'all saw that
Saul does not
see Samuel he sees someone he perceives
to be Samuel
and here you have this is by the way
was Samuel a prophet of God yes or no
absolutely so if God is not speaking to
Samuel or to Saul through prophets then
whoever this is that is impersonating
Samuel it is not Samuel
it is not Samuel
so this is this is what a very clear
example of why God said do not seek
familiar spirits
because they are spirits of devils they
are liars they are impersonating
familiar they are familiar yeah yeah I
know that person
so God says you can't trust your eyes
when you come when it comes to this
you've got to depend upon what the Bible
says
it is written it is written
first Samuel 2019 moreover the Lord will
also deliver Israel with thee into the
hand of the Philistines this is what
this spirit is saying to Saul and
tomorrow
and thy Sons be with me
now let me ask you a question
Samuel
according to the theory that people when
they die they go straight to heaven will
go straight to hell where would Samuel
be if Samuel's a prophet of God where
would he be Santa would be aware in
in heaven yeah
are y'all catching that he would be in
heaven
where would Saul be
where would Saul go
was Saul saved
was he going to heaven or hell
according to the theory of when you die
you either go straight to heaven you're
alive in heaven even though you're dead
or you're alive in hell even though
you're dead so how is it that the spirit
is telling Saul
pretending to be Samuel so apparently
Samuel's in heaven and the spirit is
telling songs hey Saul you're going to
be in heaven with me tomorrow no
you can see the deception y'all
are y'all catching this
this is a lying Spirit telling Saul
basically you're gonna die tomorrow
and death means the grave it means going
back into the Earth
all right
so what is the remedy for death
according to the Old Testament that's
our next question What is the remedy for
death according to the Old Testament I
want you to notice Hosea chapter 13
verse 14. I will Ransom them from the
power of the Grave I will redeem them
from death oh death I will be thy
plagues o grave I will be by destruction
repentance shall be hid from mine eyes
according to the Old Testament
the remedy for death
has to do
with when God's people will come out of
the Grave I got a question for you
when is it that God is going to pull
people out of the graves
it's at a very specific event what's
that event called
it's called the second coming of Jesus
according to the Old Testament
the remedy for death
is when plagues are poured out upon
death which occurs at the second coming
are you with me so far
notice again with me Isaiah 26 and verse
9. Isaiah 26 verse 19 not rather Isaiah
26 19 thy dead men shall live listen to
me thy dead men are alive
foreign
is that what the text says thy dead men
are alive
no it says thy dead men shall live
together with my dead body shall they
arise awake and sing awake huh what are
you awake from you're awake from when
you're sleeping awake and sing you that
dwell in the dust
for the do is as a dew of the herbs and
the Earth shall cast out the Dead
let me ask you a question
how many of you
would say I look forward to dying
I can't wait to die is there anyone
who is not struggling with mental
illness because that's a real thing
people struggling with mental illness
may look forward to dying so I'm not
talking about that right now I'm talking
about you have no mental illness you're
not struggling you're not depressed is
there anyone that's like man I can't
wait to die
is death anybody's hope
no now how many of you can't wait for
the resurrection
how many of us look forward to the
resurrection
yes yes why because beloved it is at the
resurrection that death is defeated
nobody walks around saying I can't wait
to die
so I can be with Jesus
no one looks forward to death we say I
can't wait for the resurrection now
again I know what you're thinking I know
where your mind is going to in the New
Testament but just hold it hold your
thought we're going to get there we're
going to get there we're almost there
we're almost done with the Old Testament
Daniel 12 2 last text I want to show you
Daniel 12 and verse 2. notice what the
Bible says and many of them that sleep
in the dust of the Earth shall awake
some to everlasting life and some to
shame and everlasting contempt beloved
Daniel 12 2 is talking about the second
coming of Christ and it is at the second
coming of Christ where the righteous
shall awake to everlasting life
and you'll see in another study that we
do at another time that it is later on
that the wicked come to life to
Everlasting shame and content all right
so
we have just painted a pretty consistent
picture in the Old Testament
in the Old Testament a soul is a living
being
when that person or that that body and
breath that's the soul
when a person dies the body goes back to
the ground and the breath goes back to
God
then the person has no consciousness
but will again be alive when Jesus comes
again he will awake out of his sleep so
according to the Old Testament it is
very clear that the dead don't know
what's going on on Earth they don't know
what's going on in heaven they are dead
okay
now let's go to the New Testament
does the the things change in the New
Testament well let's find out the first
thing I want you to see we're going to
ask the question what is a soul
according to the New Testament what is a
soul according to the New Testament well
the Bible says here in Acts 2 verse 41
then they that gladly received his word
were baptized and the same day they were
added unto them about 3
000 intangible spirits
three thousand intangible Spirits y'all
or three thousand people
what are those three thousand souls mean
three thousand people yes
so in the New Testament the soul is the
same thing as the Old Testament
y'all got it
the soul in the New Testament is the
same thing as the Old Testament they're
people living people three thousand
living people not three thousand
intangible spirits but three thousand
living people were baptized on the day
of Pentecost okay what about this let's
go to Acts chapter seven
and verse 14. uh this is
um Stephen in the middle of his of his
speech before he stoned he says this
then sent Joseph and called his father
Jacob to him and all his Kindred three
score and 15 Souls
three score and 15 what everyone
three score and 15 people that's what
the word souls mean people
people living beings
all right
so far so good well in the New Testament
what is death
is death something different in the New
Testament than it was in the Old
Testament that's the question right fair
question because a lot of times you know
things that were in the Old Testament
um you'll see things there's a new way
of doing things in the New Testament but
let's see if that's the case for death
is death the same thing in the Old
Testament as it was in the new well
let's see what the Bible says John 11.
these things said he this is Jesus and
after he saith and after he saith unto
them our friend Lazarus sleep it
but I go that I may wake him out of
sleep
then said his disciples Lord if he sleep
he shall do well how be Jesus speak of
his death
but they thought that he's had spoken of
taking of rest in sleep so hey guys we
don't have to go too far we're seeing
that in the New Testament death is
asleep just like it was in the Old
Testament
are y'all good
yeah so death is asleep in the New
Testament according to Jesus's own words
death is a sleep just as he said in the
Old Testament
how about this
what does Paul say about that
first uh first Thessalonians chapter 4
verse 13 but I would not have you to be
ignorant Brethren concerning them which
are asleep
that you sorrow not even as others which
have no hope verse 14 for if we believe
that Jesus died and rose again even sold
them also with sleep in Jesus will God
bring with him
so once again according to the New
Testament
sleep is death
sleep is the very same thing as death
all right
let's keep moving let's keep moving
we're going to go to John chapter 20
verse 16. what about Jesus what about
Jesus in John chapter 20 and verse 16
the Bible says here John 20 verse 16
Jesus saved unto her
now let me go back a little bit
so y'all remember where Jesus is on the
cross and then the thief on the cross
says remember me when you come into
paradise and then
um Jesus said verily I tell you uh today
you shall be with me in Paradise right
and there are two different ways you can
read that either Jesus is saying
you will be with me in Paradise today or
today I'm telling you that you will be
with me in Paradise in the future
so all we need to do to find out which
which way should we read the text
because there were no punctuation marks
in the original text how do we read the
text well notice what Jesus says three
days after his death
Jesus said unto Mary
Jesus saith unto her marriage she turned
herself and said unto him rabbonai which
is the same Master Jesus saith unto her
touch me not for I am not yet ascended
to my father
go to my brethren and say unto them I
will Ascend unto my father and your
father and to my God and your God so
three days after Jesus was re was dead
he us he comes out of the grave and he
says to Mary I have not yet ascended to
my Father which means the day he died he
didn't Ascend to his father
three days he didn't Ascend to his
father so he could not have meant to the
thief from the cross hey today you'll be
with me in Paradise if Jesus was not in
Paradise that day himself
are y'all with me so far
we'll talk about the Paradise in a
moment
and by the way y'all Paradise is clearly
heaven
Paradise is clearly heaven
okay so let's keep moving so again the
question is what about Jesus now I want
you to notice this here notice Matthew
chapter 28 verse 5 Matthew chapter 28
verse 5 the Bible says now this is Jesus
resurrecting
the angel answered and said unto the
woman because they're at the tomb
looking for him fear you not I know you
seek Jesus which was crucified he is not
here all right you guys pause for a
second I want you to really take these
words in he is not here
for he is risen
as he said come see the place where the
Lord lay and go quickly and tell his
disciples that he has risen from the
dead let me go back here he is not here
for he has risen
so let's reverse that
he is not here means he is risen
now listen to me carefully you guys
if he was here
it would mean that he was not what
not
risen
the angel says he is not here meaning
he's not dead
he's alive
listen to me you guys he um a person
cannot be dead and alive at the same
time
you cannot be dead in your casket while
also being in heaven
also being alive in hell
you are either dead
or alive
you cannot be dead
and Alive now watch this
Christianity as a whole agrees that if a
body was found in the Tomb
Christianity would never have existed
let me say it again you guys
if a body was found in the Tomb
Christianity would never have existed
why because it would have been evidence
that Jesus come on somebody
come on it would have been evidence that
Jesus did not rise from the dead
put us put a seven in the chat if you
catch that point
seven I don't need a one or two I need a
seven in the chat
if the body of Jesus could be produced
Christianity would be finished because
it would be evidence that Jesus did not
rise from the dead so here's what I want
you to catch you guys
the evidence that Jesus rose from the
dead was that the tomb was empty
y'all need to understand this if there's
a two if there's a body in the Tomb the
Jesus did not come back to life
imagine the disciples running around
saying Jesus alive he's in heaven and
then the Roman swords are like wait a
minute his body's right there
come on y'all
no matter how much they went around
saying no trust me he's alive I promise
you he's in a better place
Christianity would have gone nowhere
the greatest evidence of Christianity is
an empty tomb now why do I say this why
do I say this because I want you to
notice something else here
let's be consistent I want you to notice
something here in Matthew 17 Matthew 17
the Bible says here after six days Jesus
Peter James and John his brother uh
Jesus Took Peter James and John
and bring them up into a high mountain
apart
and was transfigured before them and his
face did shine as the sun and as Raymond
was light as was white as the light and
behold they appeared unto them Moses and
Elijah talking with him Pastor
everything you just said has gone out
the window hair is proof
that people are alive
you got Moses and Eliza right here
now I want y'all to check something out
here
number one
let's go to Deuteronomy
34 Verse 4. and the Lord said unto him
this is the land which I swear into
Abraham unto Isaac and unto Jacob this
is God speaking to Moses saying I will
give it unto thy seed I have caused thee
to see it with thine eyes but Thou shalt
not go over so Moses the servant of the
Lord died
there in the land of Moab according to
the word of Lord and he buried him in a
valley in the land of Moab over against
Beth pior but no man north of his
Sepulcher unto this day watch this y'all
why
according to Jude 1 verse 9 Yet Michael
the Archangel when he contended with the
devil he disputed about the body of
Moses does not bring a railing
accusation against him but said the Lord
rebuked thee so beloved watch this
if you went to Moses tomb let's say you
could find his tomb right ah I know
where Moses tomb is and you went to his
tomb
would you find a body
yes or no
the text we just read tells us that the
body of Moses was taken from the grave
Moses bodily went to heaven
you couldn't find his body why same
evidence as Christ he's risen from the
dead Moses was a special case
Resurrection
now what about Elijah
what about Elijah uh come with me
notice with me second Kings chapter 2
verse 11 and it came to pass as Eliza
and Elijah right they still went on and
talked that behold they were paired a
chariot of fire and Horses of fire and
parted them both asunder and Eliza went
up by a whirlwind into heaven so Eliza
doesn't die he goes straight into heaven
now watch this
verse 15 and when the sons of the
prophets which were to which were to
view it at Jericho saw him they said the
spirit of Elijah does rest on Elijah and
they came to meet him and bowed
themselves to the ground before him and
they said unto him behold now there
there be with thy servants 50 strong men
let them go we pray thee and seek thy
Master lest per Adventure the spirit of
the Lord has taken them up and cast them
upon some mountain or into some Valley
and he said You shall not sin and when
they urged him till he was ashamed he
said send they went there for 15 men and
they sought three days but what found
him not why didn't they find him because
he was bodily taken to heaven
are y'all catching this
he was broadly taken to heaven
so what does this mean what does this
tell us
if you want to know someone's in heaven
it's very simple
simple test you may not want to do this
test you might just want to believe by
faith that what I'm about to say is true
but dig up the grave
dig up the grade the same way that she
would prove that Jesus has not ascended
into heaven you go to his tomb bodies
there body's not there
well he's alive either he's alive or
someone stole the body
but if the body's there it is evidence
that the man is dead
and beloved I need you to understand
this because this is the very thing
being taught from the beginning of the
Bible if the body is in the Tomb the
person is dead he is not dead in the
Tomb but alive in heaven or dead in the
Tomb but alive in hell he is dead
now this is not saying that they will
not go to heaven at some point or they
will not go to hell at some point but
what it's saying is that while they are
dead
they are not alive in heaven or they are
not alive in hell they are dead
in order for them to get to heaven or to
get to hell they first must be
Resurrected
because they will bodily be in Hell or
bodily be in heaven
this is very simple beloved very simple
in fact there were people that that were
resurrected in the day of Jesus when he
died
when Jesus died watch this look what the
Bible says
Jesus you know Jesus when he cried again
with a loud voice and yielded up The
Ghost and behold the veil of the temple
was renting Twain from top to bottom and
the Earth did quick and the Rocks went
and watch this and the Grays were open
and many bodies of the Saints which
slept a rose
did you see that
the people who were resurrected in the
when Jesus died they bodily came out of
the Grave so watch this Eliza was
translated without seeing death Moses
died was buried and resurrected the
reason why these two men were especially
taken to Heaven is because Moses is a
type of all who will die be buried and
resurrected while Elijah is a type of
all who will be translated without
seeing death at the second coming of
Jesus
are y'all with me
let me show you let me show you even in
the book of Acts
50 days after Jesus's death burial in
Resurrection
Peter is speaking and he says this men
and Brethren let me freely speak unto
you of the patriarch David that he is
both dead and buried and a Sepulcher is
with us to this day in other words if
you want to check out whether David
is alive just go you know where his tomb
is
his body is in the grave
his body is in the grave he actually
literally says for David is not ascended
into the heavens but he's but he saith
himself the Lord said unto my Lord sit
thou at my right hand so what Peter was
doing was he was trying to prove that
these verses that that David wrote in
the Psalms were not talking about
himself because David is dead and in the
grave he has an ascended to heaven but
Jesus has
not beloved David is a man after God's
Own Heart why in the world would David
not be ascended to Heaven if when
everyone dies they go to heaven why is
David not ascended into heaven 50 days
after Pentecost
I'm sorry 50 days after the death of
Jesus
I want you to see the consistency
beloved
we're going to do a quick test quick
test this is the death test
the death test okay are we ready put a
one in the chat if you're ready for the
test
I'm going to ask a series of questions
and um you go ahead and put dead or
alive
Abraham Lincoln dead or alive
Abraham Lincoln dead or alive what is
your answer
you're talking with someone just
regularly talking you say yeah Abraham
Lincoln I say hey Aaron is he is he
still alive and your answer is going to
be
no he's
he's dead
okay
if you said dead
uh you were right give yourself a hand
you were right
okay uh Martin Luther King dead or alive
what's your answer
thank you
very good if if you said dead you are
correct
very good answer very good answer all
right next question last question Jesus
dead or alive
if you answered alive you are correct
and what does this demonstrate beloved
you cannot be both dead and alive at the
same time
either you are dead or you are alive so
when we talk about you know our great
grandparents today and we we don't go
around saying yeah they're alive
unless we're consciously trying to think
you know someone asks hey
um you know so you're you're a great
great uncle yeah yeah he died he's dead
the dead or dead beloved you cannot be
dead and alive at the same time the
reason we say Jesus is Alive is because
we know that the tomb was empty so
beloved if your if there is a body in
the Tomb
guess what that person is right where
God said they would be in the dust of
the ground until Jesus comes again
the Bible tells us in second Timothy 4
verse 1.
I charge thee I charge thee before God
where is that takes
all right we're just gonna go with these
John 5 28 Marvel not of this for the
hour is coming in which all that are in
the grave all that are in the grave all
that are in the grave shall hear his
voice this is Jesus speaking and shall
come forth they that have done good unto
the resurrection of life and they that
have done evil
unto the resurrection of damnation I
want you to know this the hour is coming
meaning that it's not here yet
the hour is coming
so beloved you've got to understand here
that Jesus himself is saying where are
the dead they are in the graves which is
also translated in the Bible as hell the
grave the dirt the dust of the ground
how about this
First Corinthians 15 51 behold I show
your mystery we shall not all sleep but
we shall all be changed in a moment in
the twinkling of an eye at the last
Trump
for the trumpet shall sound and the dead
shall be raised Incorruptible and we
shall be changed do you see that guys it
is at the last trump it is at the second
coming of Christ where the dead are
raised
yes I hope you're catching this
first Thessalonians 4 15. for this we
say unto you by the word of the Lord
that we which are alive and remain unto
the coming of the Lord shall not go
before them which are asleep for the
Lord himself shall descend from heaven
with a shout with the voice of the
Archangel and with the Trump of God and
watch this the dead in Christ shall rise
first when at the second coming of the
Lord the dead in Christ Moses is shall
rise first then we which are alive and
remain Eliza's shall be caught up
together with them in the cloud to meet
the Lord in the air and so shall we ever
be with the Lord all right we're almost
done guys we're almost done
I just want to talk about a few verses
in the New Testament that people will
say well what about this what about this
let's just hit those very quickly and
then I want to show you a couple things
and then we're going to close this up so
what about this this verse absent from
the body present with the Lord we are
confident I say and willing rather to be
absent from the body and to be present
with the Lord
so here's a question what does it mean
to be absent from the body and to be
present with the Lord what is Paul
talking about here well just a few
verses earlier here's what he says for
either in this Tabernacle meaning this
body this dust grown being burdened not
for that we would be uncold
but called upon that mortality might be
swallowed up of life so when he's saying
listen carefully when he's saying I I
can't wait to be absent from the body
and present with the Lord what he's
saying is I can't wait to have that to
have mortality
swallowed up by immortality
so I can be present with the Lord
forever that's what he's saying now in
this verse he doesn't tell us when that
happens
he doesn't tell us if that happens at
death or at Resurrection
because when you die you are technically
with your body still you you go back
into the dust of the ground you are
asleep in the ground
so is it at death that we become absent
from the body and present with the Lord
or is it at resurrection that we become
absent from the body and present with
the lord well guess what Paul answers
Paul answers he answers his own question
notice the text second Corinthians First
Corinthians 15 52 in a moment in the
twinkling of an eye at the last Trump at
the last Trump at the last Trump for the
trumpet shall sound and the dead shall
be raised Incorruptible and we shall be
changed for this corruptable must put on
incorruption and this what's that word
everyone this Mortal put on immortality
first Thessalonians 2 19 for what is our
hope our joy our crown of rejoicing are
not even ye in the presence of our Lord
Jesus Christ at his coming when are we
in his presence
when are we present with the Lord
at his coming
how y'all doing
okay
all right so another person brought up a
text I I think I saw it in the text
earlier
um what about feared at him that can
kill the body but cannot kill the soul
but for him that can kill the body and
the soul in hell
so there's a very simple
under explanation for this
what God is saying is look Don't Fear
the people that can bring the first
death upon you where you die but you'll
be resurrected in other words I'm
resurrecting you come back to life
either for you know for Life everlasting
life or Everlasting destruction so you
know don't fear people and and the
things that can kill that can kill the
body but
your life is Gonna Come Back
fear Him
that can destroy not just the body but
your life for all eternity in other
words fear him that can bring about the
second death yes Sam fear him that can
bring about the second death in which
you are destroyed forever for all
eternity
we're going to do a whole separate study
on our next fourth Sabbath on on
Hellfire so there's some things I'm not
going to answer today I'm going to save
it for our Hellfire discussion do the
wicked burn in hell forever or and when
do the wicked go to hell we're going to
have a whole study on that
but I want you to know
one more point I want to bring out here
and that is the parable of Lazarus and
the rich man
the pen notice what I said the parable
of Lazarus
and the rich man so I want you to note
this
um this Parable is found in Luke 16 and
how do we know it's a parable for
several reasons number one in Luke 14 7
you have the parable of the wedding
feast in Luke 14 12 same chapter the
parable of the great banquet in Luke 15
1 the parable of the lost sheep in Luke
15 8 the parable of the lost coin in
Luke 15 11 the parable of the prodigal
son in Luke 16 1 the parable of the
dishonest manager in Luke 69
the parable of the rich man and Lazarus
now why do we know that this is a
parable
well it's very simple
number one
people don't die if you if
are y'all hearing me
yes
Okay so
I'm still getting no sound
okay all right good
so what was I saying
yes
all right can you hear me now
are we good all right
see my battery died
your microphone cannot be both dead and
alive at the same time
thank you
are y'all with me if the microphone is
dead it cannot operate
it cannot operate these were freestyling
companies it cannot operate
either the mic is dead or it is alive it
is a if it is alive then then you can
hear and you can yes and there's
communication you can correspond but if
the mic is dead if the battery is gone
below
the thing cannot operate
are y'all with me
all right I'm not going to tell you that
was planned that would have been nice if
it was planned but it wasn't
but I thought why not use it as an
example
so in this Parable Lazarus goes to goes
to uh Abraham's bosom but the but the
but the rich man
he goes to hell
now watch this guys if this is literal
then
the rich man in hell is like
use your finger Lazarus first of all
How likely is it that out of all the
billions of people that are supposed to
be in hell and all the billions of
people are supposed to be in heaven the
rich man is asking Lazarus out of all
the people man you know I don't know
anybody else here because I knew no one
in my life but the beggar that was
outside my gate so let me ask him for
water it's a parable if it's literal
it's a very ridiculous story God is
using Jesus is using here a parable
number one number two remember
the rich man his body has been buried
so if he's actually in Hell how can he
be saying
take some water and dip it and drop some
water on my tongue tongue what so you're
telling me that Spirits have a have a
tongue
and fingers and they get thirsty
is Heaven and Hell close enough that
that they can talk to each other
no beloved this is clearly a parable and
it's in the context of a series of
perils now watch this
what is Jesus trying to teach in this
parable
let me break this down for you the rich
man
represents the Jewish leaders
or they got the riches of God they got
everything they they claimed to be
blessed by God the poor man
watch this y'all the poor man represents
a person that would die outside the
gates of the House of the rich man
what is the house of the rich man it's
Jerusalem
it's Jerusalem
and this guy who dies outside the gates
of the Jerusalem are outside against the
root of Jerusalem would be looked upon
as poor as a beggar as unworthy
so this man dies outside the Gates of
Jerusalem and then the Bible says that
he ascends to Abraham's Buddha he goes
to the father he is he ascends to the
father
and then in this Parable the guy in hell
is like hey send Lazarus back so that my
brothers will believe and then and then
Abraham says no you have Abraham I mean
you have Moses you have the word of God
if you don't even listen to the word of
God you will not believe even if one
rose from the dead are y'all catching
this
Lazarus beloved
is was a parable of Jesus
he is the one that was sent back from
the dead and because the Jewish leaders
rejected the Moses the law and the
prophets the way that they claimed to
have the riches of the Bible but they
rejected it so that even when Jesus rose
from the dead they still rejected it
remember Stephen Stephen is talking to
them he's given them his final summary
before they Stone them and what does
Stephen say he looks up and he says I
see Lazarus standing at the right hand
of the father
y'all get what I'm saying right I see
Jesus the one that you crucified outside
the city Gates I see Jesus standing at
the right hand of the father and what do
they do they stop their ears
and they stoned Stephen
the problem of the rich man and Lazarus
is not meant to teach that that the
wicked when the wicked die they they
immediately go to hell and when the
righteous died they immediately go to
heaven it is meant to teach that if
you're not standing on the word of God
remember how we started the sermon
we got to stand on the word of God if
you're not standing on the word of God
beloved guess what you will end up being
deceived by the enemy
you will end up being deceived by the
enemy
all right
you remember Satan's first lie we're
about to wrap this up
we're about to wrap this up you remember
how many of you remember what Satan's
first lie was
let me go to the text
Genesis 3 3 but of the fruit of the tree
which is in the midst of the garden God
has said You shall not eat of it neither
shall you touch it lest you die that's
what Eve is saying to The Serpent and
the serpent said unto the woman you
shall not surely die
Satan's lie his first lie to humanity
you are naturally immortal
don't worry about it you don't die your
soul doesn't die you will live on and on
and on God said you will die meaning you
will turn to the ground you return to
the dust you will you you will your
everything is going to shut down like
the battery the battery is going to run
out no communication you can't you you
know nothing you feel nothing which is
so merciful
because death is like a sleep you're not
in the grave like man when is Jesus
coming again no it's like when you sleep
you don't know how much time has passed
there'll be people who are in the grave
for thousands of years that when Jesus
comes again it'll be like they close
their eyes and the next thing is that
they open their eyes
God is merciful
we go through enough you know like sort
of like hell on this Earth that when we
sleep it's literally like a rest can you
imagine can you imagine like being dead
and able to see what's going on on Earth
able to see like your kids who are now
fatherless or motherless being abused by
some other person and you can't do
anything about it can you imagine what
kind of hell that would be God says I'm
gonna let you sleep
everybody's gonna sleep and then when I
come again
everybody's going to get their reward at
the same time the righteous will enter
Heaven at the same time the Wicked Will
Enter Hell at the same time we're gonna
have a whole nother study on that but I
need you to see this we're wrapping this
up listen
listen
in Revelation 18 verse 23 the Bible says
and the light of a candle shall shine no
more at all indeed and the voice of the
Bride agreement of the Bride shall be
heard no more at all indeed for thy
Merchants were the Great Men of the
Earth for by thy sorceries where all
nations deceive now you'll remember that
we learned in the Old Testament that God
is against sorcery witchcraft necromancy
so this text is telling us here that
even in the New Testament we must be
aware of the devil's magical tricks the
devil's sorcery one of which
is pretending to impersonate the dead
and the Bible says it will be by these
sorceries that the whole world is going
to be deceived what is the Bible trying
to tell us notice again with me just a
few more texts John Revelation 16 13. I
saw three unclean spirits like frogs
come out of the mouth of the Beast
another mouth of the dragon out of the
mouth of the dragon and out of the mouth
of the Beast and out of the mouth of the
false prophet for they are spirits of
devils working miracles which go forth
unto the kings of the earth and the
whole world to gather them to the battle
of the great day of God Almighty in
other words Satan is going to unleash
listen to me he's going to unleash
a barrage of Miracles
some of which will have to do with
familiar spirits
the Dead
so when we think about psychics and
Halloween and communicating and all
these Souls on TV where you know people
are you know ghost shows oh I hear the
dead we understand that this is the
devil doing deception but at the end of
time he's going to do it on on a massive
scale watch this you guys Matthew 24 24
Matthew 24 24. I hope y'all got your
seatbelts on because listen to this the
Bible says we open up with this for
there shall arise false Christ and false
prophets and shall show great signs and
wonders and someone said if it were
possible they shall deceive the very
elect Matthew 24 verse 21.
verse 21 and many false prophets shall
rise and shall deceive many now pause
for a second y'all
many false prophets shall rise
now when we typically read that text we
think yeah at the end of time you know
there's going to be a whole bunch of
false prophets that are going around yes
that is true that's true
Yes Rick
what does that word rise mean what does
that word rise mean let me show you this
word rise
this word rise
egiro the Greek
probably akin to the basis of g58
through the idea of collecting one's
faculties to awaken
whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa to awaken
that is tarouse literally from sleep
from sinning or lying or from disease
from death
whoa
many prophets y'all remember what
happened with Samuel and Saul
Saul goes to a magician and and
apparently
it's Samuel that what give me the word
y'all Rises
resurrects
comes out of but without a body
just a form
Jesus says many false prophets shall
rise so yes in one sense yeah there's
going to be people that are hey I'm a
prophet I'm a prophet but in another
sense it's as though he's saying they're
going to be spirits of the Dead coming
back claiming to be my Prophets
and if you don't understand that when
the Dead die they are dead that you
cannot be dead and alive at the same
time you even the very elect if it were
possible will be deceived
three times
Jesus confronted the enemy
and he responded it is written it is
written it is written beloved we have
Moses and the prophets we have the word
of God if we will not believe the word
of God
one will rise from the dead
and we're going to be deceived by it
we will be deceived by it
stand on the word
stand on the word do not trust your
senses and I'm not talking about it you
know I'm talking about when it comes to
this do not trust don't don't you know
be like
go to your you know spouse and be like I
don't see you I don't trust my senses
your spouse is there I'm not talking
about that I'm talking about when if you
if you get that visitation oh my
grandmother my my great great or I went
to us you know this person visited me
from the grave beloved
trust the word of God
over your senses
tell that familiar Spirit get thee
behind me
and be about your father's business
my appeal to you beloved stand on the
word don't go by what is popular
listen to me
Satan is deceiving so many how many
funerals have you been to
how many funerals have you seen where
you know you know the person
that died
just was didn't even know God
and the preacher will preach he's in
heaven looking down at us now
I know it's a thing to kind of help us
feel better
but beloved when we put people in heaven
that are not there or people even put
people in hell that are not they do I
mean people have just gone have lost
have mental issues because they think my
loved one is in Hell being burned right
now as I'm walking around doing stuff
and they are they're like how can God be
like that listen y'all the truth of the
Bible will always it it error never
makes sense
if people go straight to heaven when
they when they die why is Jesus coming
back to resurrect anybody
what is the purpose of a resurrection if
our hope is death I can't wait to die so
I can go to heaven
oh man well let's just die
no no no no our hope is not death our
hope is resurrection
our hope is resurrection
so my appeal
stand on the word of God
everything else is sinking sand stand on
the word of God Heavenly Father
thank you for speaking to us thank you
for teaching us thank you for
instructing us
Lord remind us of all we have learned
today for those who may be hearing this
for the first time or who will hear this
for the first time Lord help them to go
back to the word of God and see if these
these things are so and remind us Lord
that that one scripture does not
contradict 20 30 other scriptures that
say the same thing consistently and so
if we're trying to take one scripture
and disregard 50 other scriptures we're
coming at this the wrong way Lord help
us to see that one scripture in the
light of the other scriptures that are
clearly defined Lord please
Open the Eyes of those who are sincerely
seeking truth
thank you Lord for giving us your word
that keeps us from the deception and
darkness of this world the deception and
darkness of the enemy
help us to stand on that word is our
prayer in Jesus name amen and amen
I want to thank you all for joining us
um we're going to put up uh in the link
the salt Outreach for those of you that
want to uh uh be a part of that meeting
we're also going to uh I think we're
going to go ahead and have our Afterglow
on altar live as well so we'll put the
link up there
um God bless you guys I hope this
message has blessed you today and uh
study the show that I self-approved amen
study to show thyself approved God bless
you
thank you for worshiping with us today
if this is your first time visiting with
us we invite you to check out our
website at livingmanna.live there you
will learn more about our mission to
reach the world with the Gospel of Jesus
we have exciting life programs
throughout the week covering topics like
physical health mental health prayer
learning how to prove God's existence
and much more if you would like to
support the ministry you can click on
the tithe and offering link on our
website we ask that you continue to pray
for the church as God continues to open
doors for our programming to reach the
world thank you again for your prayers
and your support
foreign